<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Cam Daigle</title>
	<subtitle>Personal website of Cam Daigle</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/"/>
	<updated>2022-09-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://camerondaigle.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>spamerondaigle@gmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>There are three types of meetings.</title>
		<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/"/>
		<updated>2022-09-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a system – a survival mechanism, really – for classifying, planning, and
executing meetings in a way that helps keep me sane at work. I&#39;ve shared it with
enough folks for whom it was also a survival mechanism that it&#39;s now a system,
at a URL, for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-more-not-less-just-better&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Not more, not less – just better. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#not-more-not-less-just-better&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a warning, this isn&#39;t necessarily a path to having &lt;em&gt;fewer&lt;/em&gt; meetings. After
all, everyone&#39;s threshold for &#39;too many meetings&#39; is different based on what
helps them feel effective at their role, and every company&#39;s need for meetings
is dependent upon the work they&#39;re trying to accomplish. Managers generally feel
more effective when they&#39;re communicating directly with people, which means
they&#39;re generally fans of meetings. Individual contributors generally feel more
effective when they&#39;re plying their trade, so they tend to feel pulled away from
their &#39;real work&#39; when they have to attend meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s even a possibility that when you work through this system, you end up
with &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; meetings, because you have one monstrous, all-encompassing meeting
that&#39;s trying to do too many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hoping this system helps you have &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; meetings – that the people
running the meeting feel like it&#39;s worth their time to run them, and that the
people in attendance feel like their presence there &lt;em&gt;matters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&#39;s get into it: try thinking of all meetings as either &lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;
meetings, &lt;strong&gt;Feedback&lt;/strong&gt; meetings, or &lt;strong&gt;Decision&lt;/strong&gt; meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll talk about these meetings in 4 aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The goal.&lt;/strong&gt; What is this meeting type trying to accomplish?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The risks.&lt;/strong&gt; As you&#39;ll see, each of these meeting types devolves into either
a bad version of itself or literally another type of meeting if it&#39;s run poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The power dynamic.&lt;/strong&gt; There is &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; a power dynamic at play in any
meeting; you need to understand what it is in order for it to factor into
helping a meeting be productive instead of destructive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The scale.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, all meetings don&#39;t work for all audience sizes – having an
understanding of scale will help you know who to invite to what.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;status-meetings&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status Meetings &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start with what inevitably is our most common meeting type: the status
meeting. Maybe your company has weekly readouts, or daily standups. Maybe
there&#39;s a quarterly all-hands, or a monthly report. Most meetings, for better or
worse, are status meetings, even when they shouldn&#39;t be (we&#39;ll get to that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status-meetings-the-goal&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status Meetings: The Goal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings-the-goal&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a status meeting should be simply to &lt;strong&gt;disseminate information&lt;/strong&gt;.
That&#39;s it. If the attendees of the meeting come away with current and relevant
information about whatever the hell the meeting was intending to communicate,
it&#39;s done its job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status-meetings-the-scale&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status Meetings: The Scale &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings-the-scale&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scale of a status meeting can essentially be infinite. Hell, the State of
the Union address is basically a nationwide status meeting. Go nuts, as long as
your material is relevant to your audience. If it&#39;s not, you&#39;ve got problems.
Let&#39;s talk about the many ways status meetings can go sideways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status Meetings: The Power Dynamic &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power dynamic of a healthy status meeting is actually very straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The presenter has the power&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it. In a morning squad standup (the most equitable status meeting), the
person speaking is the presenter, and has the power. Even if the presenter is
presenting to the executive team, they should &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; have the power in the
meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status-meetings-devolution&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status Meetings: Devolution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings-devolution&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the goal of a status meeting is so simple, and the scale can be so
large, the risks of an individual status meeting can seem relatively benign,
especially because the bigger a meeting is, the less often it occurs (e.g. a
quarterly all-hands can be pretty boring, but at least it&#39;s only boring 4 times a year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the erosion of morale from bad status meetings doesn&#39;t happen because &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;
of them is bad, it happens because &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of them are bad. When people feel like
they&#39;re drowning in meetings, it&#39;s likely because they&#39;re having to navigate too
many status meetings – they&#39;re either feeling overwhelmed with information, or
they&#39;re feeling overwhelmed with &lt;em&gt;boredom&lt;/em&gt; as they wait their way through
readouts of information that is redundant or irrelevant to their &amp;quot;real job&amp;quot;, as
it were (which is likely not Professional Meeting Audience Member).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Status meetings, especially lots of redundant/boring status meetings, can be a
huge morale drag. Sitting in a meeting hearing information that&#39;s inactionable
doesn&#39;t help anyone feel effective except (maybe) the presenter, who themselves
is probably not loving having to deliver readouts to an indifferent audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;status-meetings-should-be-efficient-structured-and-read-only&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Status meetings should be &lt;strong&gt;efficient&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;structured&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;read-only&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#status-meetings-should-be-efficient-structured-and-read-only&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A status meeting that isn&#39;t &lt;strong&gt;efficient&lt;/strong&gt; probably just needs to be shorter –
even if that means it happens more often. Is your Product Team Monthly a 2-hour
slog? Maybe it could be a 1-hour slog, with more info in a followup email. Maybe
it could be a trim 30 minutes biweekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A status meeting that isn&#39;t &lt;strong&gt;structured&lt;/strong&gt; is probably inefficient. Different
ceremonies for different types of status meetings can really help – make sure
you have a running agenda, or a slide deck, or minutes. The most well-loved
meeting at my company is something called Design Lightning, where designers all
contribute 1-2 slides of current to a deck, which a facilitator then keys
through as each designer spends 1-2 minutes explaining their work. Snappy,
structured, usually over in under 30 minutes, with folks feeling informed and
inspired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A status meeting that isn&#39;t &lt;strong&gt;read-only&lt;/strong&gt; runs the biggest risk of all, because
once interruptions happen and the conversation commences that
the presenter/speaker has to navigate on the fly, the power of the speaker is no
longer respected, and well, buddy, you&#39;re not in a
status meeting anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your carefully-constructed status meeting &lt;strong&gt;has devolved
into a Surprise Feedback Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(As you&#39;ll see, each of these meeting types can devolve into one of the others, which is kind of
fun. I&#39;ll have a cute graphic at the end here, so you can keep reading, or just
cheat and scroll down, I won&#39;t mind.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;feedback-meetings&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feedback Meetings &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#feedback-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might feel like the &amp;quot;read-only&amp;quot; rule I&#39;m pushing for Status Meetings feels
unnecessarily restrictive. What if people have things to say? What if &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; have
things to say? Look, I understand. You probably do have things to say. They&#39;re
probably important and awesome! But as with all awesome and important things,
they deserve to matter. Catching a presenter off-guard mid-slide isn&#39;t going to
be the optimal way for them to recieve your challenge, inquiry, or insight. To
really set everyone up for productive dialogue, you need a feedback meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-meetings-the-goal&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feedback Meetings: The Goal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#feedback-meetings-the-goal&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a feedback meeting is &lt;strong&gt;for a specific person or group of people to
get the information they need about their work&lt;/strong&gt;. If the person who needs that
information gets it, the meeting is a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-meetings-the-scale&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feedback Meetings: The Scale &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#feedback-meetings-the-scale&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback meetings are very tricky to scale – too few people and you may be
excluding important voices in terms of expertise, perspective, or diversity, but
too many, and people may leave feeling unheard, or the conversation may become
unwieldy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be a good idea to scope a feedback meeting to an entire team (for
example, we have a weekly Design Crit to which all designers are invited) or
some other easy-to-grok rationale, and then make sure the meeting presenter or
facilitator is proactively making sure everyone is heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feedback Meetings: The Power Dynamic &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#feedback-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re going to talk power dynamics before risks here, because the power dynamic in feedback meetings can be incredibly tricky. If you&#39;ve
scaled your audience properly, everyone involved has expertise, domain
knowledge, and input ready to deploy when the moment is right – but sometimes
you&#39;re just presenting to management or leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, the person asking for feedback does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; hold the power in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you have a monthly review with your leadership team. This meeting might
even be &lt;em&gt;called&lt;/em&gt; a Monthly Status Meeting, but it&#39;s likely not a Status Meeting by this
system, because you often get &lt;em&gt;feedback&lt;/em&gt; in the form of inquiries,
approval/disapproval, or simply gut reactions to the work you&#39;re presenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of dynamic is most at risk of devolution: you may feel compelled to
act directly on feedback from a superior mid-meeting, especially if said superior
isn&#39;t aware of the power they hold and are quick to provide gut reactions that
cause you worry or anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a smaller scale, this could even happen with, say, a designer presenting
their designs to their peers – if one of those peers holds more sway due to
status, seniority, or even just privilege, the presenter may have to really
fight the temptation to devolve the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, let&#39;s picture a situation where your company made a structural
change and is now hosting a Q&amp;amp;A session about it. In that case, the leadership
again holds the power, but is now inviting feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least in my experience, company leadership isn&#39;t that likely to switch
tactics midstream – their challenge is to be aware of the power they hold as a
presenter to keep the feedback meeting rewarding and relevant to the people
providing feedback through&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-meetings-devolution&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feedback Meetings: Devolution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#feedback-meetings-devolution&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the power imbalance and the stakes can be fairly high in a
feedback meeting, there are many pitfalls to watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is simply that feedback itself can spin out of control. Entire
other articles and columns and books have been written just about how to
compose, deliver, and recieve contructive feedback; I can&#39;t do that here, this
page is long enough as it is. In this context, let&#39;s instead
focus on the meeting itself and two big risks you need to navigate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respect the boundaries set up by the presenter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presenter simply needs to collect relevant information so they
can step away after the meeting, weigh and consider it, and move forward from there. It&#39;s in their
best interest to define the playing field for that information as clearly as
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, instead of a generic &#39;what do you think?&#39;, they could be open about being unsure
about their wording choice, or their color choice, or whether the overall
structure of their work makes sense. Whatever they specify, it should be
respected by the folks providing that feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the second risk, which I think is the most crucial:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t make any decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment the presenter stops &lt;em&gt;recieving&lt;/em&gt; feedback and starts &lt;em&gt;reacting&lt;/em&gt; to it,
you&#39;re in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my world (product design), this looks like a product designer suddenly
whipping open Figma and doing a little &amp;quot;how about now?&amp;quot; dance mid-meeting.  Even
if that designer is &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; and the feedback they&#39;re getting is &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;,
they&#39;re eating up everyone else&#39;s time, who now have to wait their turn as
pixels get pushed around, or join into the ad-hoc design session, which is now
at risk of being incredibly messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialogue is fine! Conversations are great. Feedback should be recieved, recorded
and followed up on. But once you start &lt;em&gt;deciding&lt;/em&gt; things – whether you&#39;re moving
a mockup around or just tweaking a slide or a document, you&#39;ve now &lt;strong&gt;devolved&lt;/strong&gt; your
feedback meeting into a &lt;strong&gt;Bad Feedback Meeting That&#39;s Actually A Surprise
Decision Meeting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This devolution is often unintentional and the result of an unrecognized power
dynamic. Keeping a feedback meeting from devolving requires the powerful voices
in the world to stay aware of the power they wield when they speak up, and
requires them to make sure the presenter feels &lt;em&gt;safe&lt;/em&gt; to simply &lt;em&gt;receive&lt;/em&gt; even
the most incisive, earthshaking feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decision-meetings&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision Meetings &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the Status Meeting might feel restrictive to the person looking to have
their voice heard in a meeting, the Feedback Meeting might feel like it&#39;s
limiting your ability to Actually Do Something. So let&#39;s talk about Decision
Meetings, which exist specifically to fill that need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decision-meetings-the-goal&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision Meetings: The Goal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings-the-goal&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a decision meeting is to &lt;strong&gt;present one or more problems and make a
decision about them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds easy, but it&#39;s not, especially since people don&#39;t often identify decision
meetings very well! In my experience these meetings are the rarest in terms of
quantity, for two main reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;decisions-often-don-t-get-their-own-meetings&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decisions often don&#39;t get their own meetings. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decisions-often-don-t-get-their-own-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their absence, decisions tend to get made through less-healthy means – like
somewhere inside a chaotic Feedback Meeting, or silently by someone just making
a call so they can keep moving, or in a 1:1 between two people that are tired of
waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;decision-meetings-are-often-misidentified&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision meetings are often misidentified. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings-are-often-misidentified&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of meetings that are actually decision meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your team gets together Monday to make sure everyone has work to do that week.
This might masquerade as &amp;quot;Monday Sync&amp;quot;, but it&#39;s not a Status Meeting, because
you&#39;re deciding together what everyone is working on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your team runs 2-week sprints and has a Session Planning meeting. Yeah, that&#39;s
a decision meeting. Actually most planning meetings are decision meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your team has a monthly backlog grooming session. Yep, that&#39;s decision time,
baby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decision-meetings-the-scale&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision Meetings: The Scale &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings-the-scale&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision meetings should be your smallest type of meeting. Everyone should be a
stakeholder and participant in the work being done, and should take an
active role in the process of producing said decision(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the meeting is too small, you&#39;re risking &amp;quot;why wasn&#39;t I consulted&amp;quot;-type
messages later. If it&#39;s too big, you&#39;re risking folks not feeling like their
voice is heard, or simply giving them more meeting fatigue when they could be
doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decision-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision Meetings: The Power Dynamic &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings-the-power-dynamic&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision meetings are one place where the existing power dynamic is actually a
key aspect of the meeting&#39;s success rather than something that you need to watch
out for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To be clear, when I say &amp;quot;power&amp;quot; here, I specifically mean power in terms of
professional role definition, not forms of privilege that exhibit as power. The
senior represenative, or manager, or director, not simply the loudest person or
the one who&#39;s been around the longest.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply mean that someone needs to be &lt;strong&gt;accountable&lt;/strong&gt; for the decision that&#39;s
being made. In a company dynamic with healthy roles and responsibilI Read About How There Are 3 Meeting Typesities, that
means the most powerful person in the room is responsible – for taking notes,
facilitating discussion, including everyone&#39;s voice, and producing not only the
decision, but notes &amp;amp; information that contextualize it for anyone that needs
the paper trail later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decision-meetings-devolution&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Decision Meetings: Devolution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#decision-meetings-devolution&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s your devolution point, bringing us full circle to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you just get out of a meeting where the team had a conflict or issue but no decision
was made? You were probable subject to a Pretty Terrible Status Meeting. Or,
maybe someone took notes and is going to adjust something, in
which case that person probably has a sour taste in their mouth from having to
experience a Stressful Feedback Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, you sure as hell didn&#39;t get a decision made that helps the team feel
satisfied, empowered, and focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-promised-you-an-infographic&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;I Promised You An Infographic &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#i-promised-you-an-infographic&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here ya go. It really all boils down to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-block&quot; src=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/img/3-meeting-type-triangle.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Visualization of 3
meeting types&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;okay-what-now&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Okay, What Now? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/three-types-of-meetings/#okay-what-now&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this system is as helpful for you as it has been for me! If you&#39;re interested in
a more expanded, &lt;em&gt;presentational&lt;/em&gt; form of this info, say a call or workshop, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:me@camerondaigle.com&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and we can chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, hey, these are my ideas i shared with you – if you found them helpful
and might even use them to appear a More Qualified Professional in a way
that profits you or your business, I&#39;d really appreciate if you threw some cash
my way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;chaching&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://buy.stripe.com/14k7ta6ozfcE3oQ3cc&quot;&gt;Pay Me Money&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>This is my fourth post.</title>
		<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/posts/fourthpost/"/>
		<updated>2018-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://camerondaigle.com/posts/fourthpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Organically grow the holistic world view of disruptive innovation via workplace diversity and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring to the table win-win survival strategies to ensure proactive domination. At the end of the day, going forward, a new normal that has evolved from generation X is on the runway heading towards a streamlined cloud solution. User generated content in real-time will have multiple touchpoints for offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-header&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Section Header &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/fourthpost/#section-header&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalize on low hanging fruit to identify a ballpark value added activity to beta test. Override the digital divide with additional clickthroughs from DevOps. Nanotechnology immersion along the information highway will close the loop on focusing solely on the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>This is my third post.</title>
		<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/posts/thirdpost/"/>
		<updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://camerondaigle.com/posts/thirdpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Organically grow the holistic world view of disruptive innovation via workplace diversity and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-diff-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-diff-js&quot;&gt;// this is a command&lt;br /&gt;function myCommand() {&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token inserted-sign inserted language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token prefix inserted&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;	&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; counter &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token deleted-sign deleted language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token prefix deleted&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;	counter&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;// Test with a line break above this line.&lt;br /&gt;console.log(&#39;Test&#39;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring to the table win-win survival strategies to ensure proactive domination. At the end of the day, going forward, a new normal that has evolved from generation X is on the runway heading towards a streamlined cloud solution. User generated content in real-time will have multiple touchpoints for offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-header&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Section Header &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/thirdpost/#section-header&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalize on low hanging fruit to identify a ballpark value added activity to beta test. Override the digital divide with additional clickthroughs from DevOps. Nanotechnology immersion along the information highway will close the loop on focusing solely on the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>This is my second post.</title>
		<link href="https://camerondaigle.com/posts/secondpost/"/>
		<updated>2018-07-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://camerondaigle.com/posts/secondpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Organically grow the holistic world view of disruptive innovation via workplace diversity and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-header&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Section Header &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/secondpost/#section-header&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/firstpost/&quot;&gt;First post&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://camerondaigle.com/posts/thirdpost/&quot;&gt;Third post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring to the table win-win survival strategies to ensure proactive domination. At the end of the day, going forward, a new normal that has evolved from generation X is on the runway heading towards a streamlined cloud solution. User generated content in real-time will have multiple touchpoints for offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalize on low hanging fruit to identify a ballpark value added activity to beta test. Override the digital divide with additional clickthroughs from DevOps. Nanotechnology immersion along the information highway will close the loop on focusing solely on the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
